André Lucas de Sousa Pinto

Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer

portfolio.andrelucax.com · linkedin.com/in/andrelucax · github.com/andrelucax andrelucax@gmail.com · +55 (61) 98231-4376 · Brazil



Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering from the University of Brasília (UnB). Has experience in designing secure, well-tested, and scalable softwares using agile methodologies. Enthusiastic about web development, mobile development, home automation and games.

EDUCATION

Universidade de Brasília Brasília, DF, Brazil Software Engineer 2017 - 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

09/2021 - Present Full Stack Developer | Lacuna Software | Brazil

Developing software for registration authorities following ICP-Brasil standards. Participating in all stages of development, including requirement gathering and analysis, client meetings, database modeling, backend and frontend. Working on all features of the software, such as video conferencing, biometric data collection, digital certificate issuance, digital signature and automatic email sending. Developed unit, integration, and E2E tests, establishing standards that were adopted as the basis for the company's projects. Worked on existing projects developing new functions, maintenance, code improvements and bug fixes. Developed a standard for multi-tenant applications. Developed real-time communication system for biometric authentication validation using SignalR. Updated .NET and Angular frameworks for various systems, including the company's foundational project.

03/2021 - 08/2021Intern | Federal Court of Accounts (TCU) | Brazil

Maintaining and developing new applications for internal use.

09/2020 - 02/2021

Developing an application for a pet shop from scratch.

Intern | Companhia da Terra | Brazil



SKILLS

Languages C# | JavaScript | TypeScript | C++ | C | Python | SQL | HTML | CSS | LATEX

Databases MSSQL | Postgres | Oracle SQL

Frameworks & Libraries .NET | ASP.NET | EF | SignalR | Playwright | MSTest | XUnit | Angular | Django | Django

Restframework | React | React Native

Docker | Git | | AWS | Figma | Jira Tools

Others REST | Swagger | CI/CD | Clean Code | Microservices | Distributed Systems | Frontend |

Backend | Full Stack

CERTIFICATES & GRANTS

From Zero to Hero: Unit testing for C# Developers 2023 From Zero to Hero: Integration testing in ASP.NET Core 2023

